

## **Profile**

I'm a UX Designer with a software design background.

Over the past 16 years I've seen all different aspects of the development process: gathering user and business requirements, designing, developing, testing, implementing and managing complex applications. I'm a certified Scrum Master.

I'm passionate about designing and testing usercentered products - whether it's a prototype or the final result.

I am currently looking for a new opportunity where I can combine my past experience with my passion for UX design.



jopped@gmail.com



06-24156959



www.joppedekker.nl



www.linkedin.com/in/in/joppe.dekker



https://twitter.com/jopped

# Joppe Dekker

UX Designer | Business analyst | Functional designer

# Working experience

## 2016 - 2017 Functional designer (DevOps), Vivat Verzekeringen

As a functional designer, I am responsible for creating and maintaining functional design specifications for multiple complex back office systems. I am part of a multidisciplinary DevOps-team focused on the maintaining complex back office applications.

#### Main tasks:

- Gathering and prioritizing internal (business) requirements from users, product owners, and other stakeholders
- Designing user interfaces, creating user flows and writing functional and technical specifications
- Develop and execute test cases for the functional acceptance tests
- Develop test cases for and coordinating the user acceptance tests
- Implementation of the changes

#### *Projects:*

 Application management and implementation of several Robotic Process Automation solutions

## 2009 - 2016 Functional designer, Vivat Verzekeringen

As a functional designer, I am responsible for creating and maintaining functional design specifications for multiple complex back office systems. I am part of a multidisciplinary DevOps-team focused on the maintaining complex back office applications.

#### Main tasks:

- Gathering and prioritizing internal (business) requirements from users, product owners, and other stakeholders
- Designing user interfaces, creating user flows and writing functional and technical specifications
- Develop and execute test cases for the functional acceptance tests
- Develop test cases for and coordinating the user acceptance tests
- Implementation of the changes

#### **Projects:**

- Designing and testing the mandate system (SEPA)
- Designing and testing complex batch programs that create custom files for external parties
- Designing and customizing our departments Sharepoint site
- Introduction of Scrum methodology in our team

## Certificates

**UX Certified program** 

Careerfoundry **June 2018** 

Courses as part of this program:

- UX Fundamentals
- UX Immersion
- UX Specialization: Frontend development for designers

#### **Professional Scrum master I**

Scrum.org December 2014

## **TMAP NEXT Testengineer**

Exin

February 2014

#### ASL<sub>2</sub>

Fxin

February 2017

## Skills

- User-Centered Design
- Competitive Analysis
- Requirements engineering
- Information analysis
- User Personas
- Information architecture
- User Flows
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Functional specifications
- Technical specifications
- User acceptance testing
- Usability testing
- Preference testing



jopped@gmail.com



06-24156959



www.joppedekker.nl



www.linkedin.com/in/ in/joppe.dekker



https://twitter.com/ jopped

# Working experience

2002 - 2009 **Application manager, SNS REAAL Groep** 

As an application manager, I was responsible for the functional application management of several complex back office applications (CRM)

#### Main tasks:

- Analyzing and solving problems
- · Responsible for the change management
- Reviewing user flows, wireframes and functional specifications
- Develop and execute testcases for the functional acceptance tests
- Develop testcases for and coordinating the user acceptance tests
- · Implementation of the changes

## **Education**

#### 2017-2018 **UX Certified program, Careerfoundry**

An intensive training program for UX Designers, specializing in UX process, methodology and skills like wireframing and prototyping

1997 - 2001 Bachelor's Degree Business economics, HES Amsterdam

HBO-Fulltime, business economics, specializing in Logistic Management

1990 -1997 **HAVO and VWO, Da Vinci-college Purmerend** 

## Courses

2016	Communicating in an assertive and self-confident way
2015	Exam training IREB Foundation
2013	Business- and Information analysis
2012	CMMI for development
2011	Functional design specifications for administrative systems
2010	Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt
2005 - 2006	Several internal courses on Application management
	(ITIL, Testing according to TMAP, Querying with SQL)

## **Tools and methods**

## **UX Tools:**

- Optimal workshop
- Sketch
- Invision
- UsabilityHub
- Balsamiq
- Methods: Incident/Change management tools: Scrum
  - TFS
  - ServiceNow

#### Data analysis tools:

- MS Access
- SQL

# Volunteer experience

Waterfall

Kanban

2008 - now Committee member Stichting Constant van Gestel Fonds and webmaster of www.stichtingconstantvangestel.nl

1999 - 2011 Writer for the glossy magazine Aniway. Writing reviews about Japanese animation, comics and computer games.

# **Hobbies and interests**

Meetups, movies, board games, Virtual Reality, computer games, Japanese animation, comics and manga.